International Fur and Leather Workers Union Records 5676
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Fur and Leather Workers Union Records
1913-1966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Fur and Leather Workers Union
5676
33.33 cubic feet
33.3 linear ft.
Reports, pamphlets, correspondence, minutes, proceedings, photographs, records.
The records, 1913-1955, comprise General Executive Board minutes, administrative records, local union correspondence, and papers of union officers. Well documented are the union's organizing efforts, the internal struggles against corruption, and the radical activities of its members. Much material pertains to the effects of conservative pressures on its leaders - particularly Ben Gold - to renounce their radical persuasion.
3338481
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 30, 1986
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, May 04, 2015
Scope and Contents
The collection spans the years 1913-1955 (bulk 1923-1955). It consists of official records, such as convention proceedings and General Executive Board meetings; office files (correspondence and financial records); local files (fur, leather, and Joint Board); subject files; and publications and miscellaneous. The records include union publications, broadsides, and photographs. The material documents particularly well the union's organizing efforts, the internal struggles against corruption, and the radical activities of its members. Also documented are the ethnic membership of the union, mostly Jewish and Greek, and its progressive and political bent. The records include documents pertaining to government prosecution of communist union members - prominently Ben Gold - but others as well. They give insights into the devastating effects of McCarthy-era anti-communist pressure on militant unions and their leaders.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5685: Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Records 5685: Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Records 5924: International Fur and Leather Workers Union Additional Records 6094: UAW Public Review Boaard Decisions
Leather workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Fur workers -- Labor unions -- United States; International Fur and Leather Workers' Union.; International Fur and Leather Workers Union of the United States and Canada; Gold, Ben.; Green, William, 1872-1952.
3338481
- Proposed drafts of original constitution, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  "Record of First Meeting (June 16, 1913) of the Furriers Convention," 8 p.
- "Minutes and Report of the 2nd Biennial Convention, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  6/7-11/15.
- President's Report; General Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  June 7th
- Related convention documents, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  speech by Samuel Gompers, resolutions, telegrams, draft constitutional amendments, (many handwritten documents).
- Related convention documents, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes and reports of convention, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  June 4-9
- Minutes and reports of convention, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Related convention documents, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  telegrams, correspondence, original credentials.
- "Minutes of the Sub-Committee and General Executive Board Meetings of the International Fur Workers Union, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  (1 bd. vol.), 128 p.
- "Minutes of the Sub-Committee and General Executive Board Meetings, International Fur Workers Union, 1919-1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  (1 bd. vol.)
- "Minutes of the Sub-Committee and General Executive Board Meetings, International Fur Workers Union, 1919-1922 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  (1 bd. vol.), (duplicate).
- "Report of the Proceedings of the 4th Bi-Annual Convention of the International Fur Workers Union, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  (1 bd. vol.).
- "Minutes of the Bi-Annual Meeting of the General Executive Board of the International Fur Workers Union, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  January 8-11
- "Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting of the International Fur Workers Union, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  March 3-6, 37 p.
- Minutes of the Meetings of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  January-December
- "Report of the Proceedings of the 5th Biennial Convention of the International Fur Workers Union, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  June 5-10, (1 bd. vol.), 543 p.
- Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting of the International Fur Workers, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  January 6-8
- Minutes of the General Executive Board Meetings held in Philadelphia; Report of the General President, Fifth Biennial Convention, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  May 31-June 3, June 1922.
- Minutes of the General Executive Board and Sub-Committee Meetings, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  June 9-December 15
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Montreal, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  January 8-11, and related documents.
- To the General Executive Board Meeting, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  January 8-10, Report of the President.
- Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting held in Boston, Massachusetts, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  July 26-28, and related documents.
- Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting held in Boston, Massachusetts, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Minutes of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  January 22-December 4
- Minutes of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Report of proceedings of the 6th Biennial Convention, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  May 12-17, (1 vol.).
- Report of the General Executive Board to the Convention, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  May 12-17, and related documents.
- Report of the General Executive Board to the Convention, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Toronto, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  January 3-5
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Chicago, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  May 5-7, and related documents.
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Chicago, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Proceedings of the International Fur Workers Union, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  November 6-17
- Proceedings of the International Fur Workers Union, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Proceedings of the International Fur Workers Union, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Report of the General Executive Board to the 7th Convention of the International Fur Workers Union, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  November 4th
- Report of the General President to the General Executive Board Meeting; Report of the General Secretary-Treasurer to the General Executive Board Meeting, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  January 5th
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, Montreal, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  January 5th-10th.
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, Atlantic City, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  August 6-9, and related documents.
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, Atlantic City, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Boston, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  November 2nd
- Minutes of a special General Executive Board Meeting held in Boston, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  November 17th
- Miscellaneous correspondence and handwritten minutes, (some are Sub-Committee minutes), 1925 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Montreal, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  January 14-18
- Report of the General President to the General Executive Board, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  January 14th
- Report of Organizer Pietro Lucchi to the General Executive Board and Report of the General Secretary-Treasurer, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Minutes of meetings of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Minutes of meetings of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Minutes of meetings of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous and delegates credentials, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Minutes of the General Executive Board held in Montreal, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  March 9-12
- Report of the General President and the General Secretary-Treasurer, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  March
- Miscellaneous minutes, reports, etc., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous minutes, reports, etc., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Minutes of meetings of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  February-December
- Convention Documents, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Form letter re 10th Convention re situation and condition of union in New York City, 5 p., signed "New York Delegates," May 12; Telegrams of greetings etc. re convention; miscellaneous documents re membership.
- Copies of completed credential certificates, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Minutes of the Canadian Conference held in Montreal, Official Report by the International Convention Unity Committee, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  November 9-10, 15 p.; May 28, 8 p.
- Correspondence (form letters), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  re announcement of meetings re problems with Local 70, etc, and miscellaneous documents.
- Correspondence (form letters), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence (form letters), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Minutes of a meeting of the General Executive Board held in Asbury Park, New Jersey, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  January 25-28
- Minutes of a meeting of the General Executive Board held in St. Paul, Minnesota, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  May 11-14
- Minutes of a conference called to propose to aid situation in Winnipeg and unionization of shops of A. Hollander and Son, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  June 9, "Resolution on Unity in the Ranks of the Fur Workers."
- Reports of Vice-Presidents and related documents, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Misc. convention correspondence and related documents, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Misc. convention correspondence and related documents, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Minutes of the General Executive Board Meeting held in Atlantic City, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  June 23-26
- Resolutions, correspondence and form letters, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  re meetings of the General Executive Board
- Resolutions, correspondence and form letters, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Summary of proceedings of the 13th Biennial Convention, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Minutes of a conference of representatives of locals of New York and Brooklyn re American Labor Party campaign and building reconstruction loan certificates.
- Correspondence from locals giving their actions, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  re the convention report.
- Correspondence re convention and announcements of meetings, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Correspondence re convention and announcements of meetings, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Atlantic City, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  January 4-7, plus various reports.
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Atlantic City, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Atlantic City, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board held in Atlantic City, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Minutes of meeting of General Executive Board, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  June 12-15, plus various reports.
- Minutes of meeting of General Executive Board, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Minutes of meeting of General Executive Board, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Misc. correspondence, resolutions, financial documents, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Executive Board Report to the Annual Convention of the Leather Division of the IFLWU, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  held in Boston, April 27-28, Summary of proceedings and decisions of same.
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  held in Atlantic City, Sic. 17-20
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Minutes of meetings of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  August-October
- Minutes of the Canadian Conference, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  held in Saratoga Springs, June 21st
- Summary of proceedings of the 14th Biennial Convention, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  May 10-16, Resolutions, etc.
- Minutes of Sub-Committee, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  January-October
- Misc. correspondence re meetings, etc, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Proceedings of the Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  December 8-11, 1943, 233 p.
- Report of B. Gold to General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  December 7, 1943, 44 p.
- Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  May 17-20, 1943.
- Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Meeting of the General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Reports to General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  by officers, districts, locals, committees, etc.
- Reports to General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Reports to General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Minutes of meetings of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  January-October 1943.
- Proceedings of International Executive Board Meeting, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  May 8-14, 1944.
- Proceedings of International Executive Board Meeting, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  May 21, 1944.
- Minutes of meeting of the Sub-Committee of the General Executive Board, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  January 20 and 25, 1944.
- Report to the International Executive Board by President Gold, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  September 24, 1945, 63 p.; misc. reports.
- Reports to the International Executive Board by Gold, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  January 13, 1947 and November 21, 1947.
- Reports of district directors including the "Endicott Report, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  November 17, 1947 by George Pershing, 7 p.
- Misc. form letters, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  re bases, statements, etc. of the Executive Board.
- Proceedings of the International Executive Board, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  May 11-16 and 23, 1948, 60 p.
- Proceedings of the International Executive Board, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Proceedings of the International Executive Board, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  May 28, 1950, 66 p.
- Proceedings of the International Executive Board, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  June 4-8, 1951, 462 p.
- Proceedings of the International Executive Board, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Proceedings of the International Executive Board, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  December 3-7, 1951, 112 p.
- panoramic photos - 8th Annual Convention -International Fur Workers Union of U.S. & (?), Washington, D.C. June 14, 1927; 17th Biennial Convention, International Fur and Leather Workers Union of the United States and Canada, C.I.O., Steep Dep, 1927-1948 (Box 5OP, Folder 1)
- Proceedings of the International Executive Board, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  May 5-8; Report of Furriers Joint Council to the International Executive Board, December 1-5
- Report of Furriers Joint Council to International Executive Board, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  November 30th-December 3rd and misc.
- Summary of proceedings of 20th Biennial Convention, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  May 2nd-8th
- Proceedings of Special Executive Board Meeting, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  December 10th-12th
- Proceedings of Special Executive Board Meeting, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Proceedings of Special Executive Board Meeting, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Proceedings of Special Executive Board Meeting, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Proceedings of Special Executive Board Meeting, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Report of International Executive Board; Committee on Officers; Introductions.
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Joint Council; Fur Division Joint Board; District 1.
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  District 2, District 3, District 4, District 5.
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Locals 2, 3, 4 and 122; Locals 79-87-213; Locals 135, 140, 145
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Anti-Discrimination; Canada; Fisherman; Fur and Leather worker.
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Gold Case.
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Leibowitz, Sam; Potash; Schneider-Klig.
- 20th Biennial Convention Reports, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Tasks of Our Union; Texas; Trade Union Veterans Committee; Conclusions.
- Misc. convention form letters and related documents., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- International Executive Board, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Reports, minutes, form letters, list of members, financial data (Gold, Feinglass, Lucchi).
- International Executive Board, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Special convention called to consider proposed merger with Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Includes correspondence, delegation lists, resolutions, statements, reports, agreement, telegrams re proposed merger.
- Special convention called to consider proposed merger with Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Copies of form letters sent to locals, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Re: special convention and how they determine number of delegates able to attend.
- Copies of form letters sent to locals, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Copies of form letters sent to locals, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America - International Executive Board, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Includes form letters, lists of locals, bulletins, minutes, photograph of International Executive Board.
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America - International Executive Board, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- American Federation of Labor (AFL), 1923-1926 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  letter to New York City unions, June 13th, from a Special Committee of the AFL re dealing with Communists; release by same committee re Mineola cases; circular letter asking organized labor to ignore Fur Workers (Gold) pleas for funds to support strikers; lengthy report of the Special Committee re investigation of internal affairs of the International Fur Workers; correspondence between William Green, Gold and Schachtman re investigation.
- AFL, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  letter from Schachtman to William Green asking for continued support in restoring "The International Fur Workers to its erstwhile normal condition of being a trade union organization and not a tail of any political party or clique"; re the reorganization attempts of the union by the AFL; re police protection assured by the Communist fur workers; includes release, letters, bulletin re fight between International and Joint Board.
- AFL, 1928-1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  includes releases, correspondence, form letters re rejection of pleas for reinstatement by Communist faction of fur workers; attendance of meetings called by Communists; letter, 3/19/36, from Green to Lucchi re collective bargaining and employer's organizations; and routine.
- AFL, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  April-December; letter from Greek Local 70 to President Green re terrorist tactics of Ben Gold, Manager of Industrial Needle Trades Workers Union against Local 70; re financial per capita tax payments; correspondence between Lucchi and President Green re problems in organizing efforts in Manitoba, Canada; strike situation in Winnipeg; 6 p. "Report of the 56th Annual Convention of the AFL at Tampa, Florida by delegates Pietro Lucchi, Samuel Mindel, Harry Begoon" re suspension of the CIO; and routine.
- AFL, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  April - between Green and Lucchi re two members arrested for union activity - Lucchi requests Green to write to the attorney; re union activities in California and Washington State; and routine.
- Abelson, Paul, 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Impartial Chairman and Chairman of Conference Committee of the Fur Industry - correspondence re negotiation meetings and arrangements; and routine.
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  correspondence and working papers re Fur Workers merger with Meat Cutters.
- American Communications Association, 1939-1954 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  between Ben Gold and Joseph P. Selly, President of the ACA re oppostion of Brownell-Butler union licensing bill - correspondence, statements; with Abe Feinglass re ACA resolutions adopted at their convention.
- American Jewish Labor Council, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  routine form letter (Ben Gold, President of American Jewish Labor Council).
- American Labor Party, 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Includes Declaration of Principles of the New York State American Labor Party; correspondence between Pietro Lucchi and Elinore Herrick re meetings of Executive Committee of which Lucchi is a member; broadsides; form letters.
- American Labor Party, 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  routine correspondence, form letters, statements.
- American Trade Union Council of the National Committee for Labor Israel, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  routine, form letters.
- American Youth Conference, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  routine.
- America's Wage Earners' Protective Conference, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  form letters, releases and routine correspondence.
- Anonymous, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  two letters from unsatisfied workers (unsigned).
- Apostol, John (Vice-President), 1937 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  correspondence with Pietro Lucchi re charges against Apostol.
- Applications - general (applications for employment), 1945 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Axelrod, Sol (organizer: St. Louis), 1942 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  routine correspondence re payment of salary, etc.
- A General, 1927-1936 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  form letter and leaflet by All Peoples Party; form letter from Alabama Federation of Labor re attack on the labor movement; and routine.
- A General, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  correspondence from members of the New York Joint Council asking Gold to conduct a recount in recent election; and routine.
- A General, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- A General, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- A General, 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- A General, 1947-1954 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  includes agreement between Amalgamated Meat Cutters and International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT), 1954, and routine.
- Bartel, Philip, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  routine re printing office supplies.
- Baxter, Charles (organizer: Ohio), 1941 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  routine re salary payments.
- Beckman, Isidore (organizer: Cleveland and Buffalo), 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  correspondence re the organizing drives; 8 p. report by Beckman to the General Executive Board Meeting, January 1937; 2 p. letter to Gold re activities and situation in Buffalo, 7/20/37; 3 p. letter, 8/4/37, re situation in Cleveland; includes broadsides entitled "All Tannery Workers of Buffalo"; and routine.
- Beckman, Isidore (organizer: Cleveland and Buffalo), 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Begoon, Harry (General Secretary-Treasurer), 1927-1940 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  includes form letters to locals re new Communist move to organize an opposition union; misc. and rountine.
- Berland, Samuel (organizer: Leather, Local 43), 1942 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  routine re salary.
- Berry, George L. (President International Printing Pressmen and Assistants Union), 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 31)